Navneet Das

Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India



navneetdas53@gmail.com



8802151814



linkedin.com/in/navneet-das

Summary

Software Development Engineering is the domain that can be heavily exploited to solve several problems across markets, and I am fascinated by the application of its concepts in getting scalable solutions for any problem in hand.

I have 2+ YoE working with several projects, which fetched me exposure to diverse fields and helped me gain insights into how an organisation operates. I am capable of working in a challenging and demanding environment, which brings the best out of me.

I have demonstrated my experience with AWS, Java, Software design, C#, ASP.NET MVC 5 (.NET framework), Mockito/JUnit, API/QA/Workflow/Pipeline and Test automation, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, jQuery, DOM, Bootstrap, C++, Python, Git, SQL/MySQL, Web applications, Agile methodologies, Linux etc.

I have worked with firms who are into e-commerce, finance-tech, and software delivery.

Apart from Software Development, I love competitive coding and have good problem-solving skills. I have been a regular problem solver on various online judges.

Experience



💫 Software Engineer II - Backend (CD)

Harness

Jan 2022 - Present (6 months +)

- Worked on Harness Delegate Selection improvements for ECS based Deployments.
- Worked on Error Handling betterment for AWS CloudFormation Continuous Delivery.
- Worked on Infrastructure Logging betterment for Harness NextGen from 0 to 1.
- Worked on ECS Task Definitions Continuous Delivery for AWS SDK Payloads.
- Worked on adding rsa-sha2-256/512 algorithms support to patched JSch library for SSH auth.
- Worked on AWS CloudFormation based API and Workflow/Pipeline Automations in QA environment.
- Took part in On-call support activities including QA and Prod environment sanity and debugging.
- Worked on AWS CloudFormation Continuous Delivery improvements for Git based template rendering.
- Joined as a Software Engineer for Continuous Delivery Platform (Backend) Team.

clear

Software Engineer I

Clear

Aug 2020 - Jan 2022 (1 year 6 months)

- Worked on launching ITR-5 JSON generation for individuals and tax experts.
- Worked on launching Amazon Alexa campaign for TaxCloud for attracting more users to the platform.
- Worked on a backend service handling APIs related to Income Tax Portal responsible for tax filings.
- Worked on launching ITR filings for 2021 (ITR-1, 2, 3 & 4) for TaxCloud users via an app from 0 to 1.

- Worked with Electron framework and Puppeteer for ClearTax desktop app responsible for tax filings.
- Worked on testing and fixing of JSON generation for ITR-3 and 4 for individuals and tax experts.
- Worked on a PDF parsing library replacement responsible for Form 16 parsing for tax filings.
- Designed system fundamentals of a New Backend Service responsible for tax filing API calls.
- Upgraded and modified queries for OrmLite for a backend service responsible for tax filing API calls.
- Added Salesforce LeadSquared integration on TaxCloud to fetch key user actions from 0 to 1.
- Extended Redis rate limiting for email Invitations for referral service on ClearTax to prevent false-play.
- Did few DB optimizations including index additions and foreign key related changes for speed-ups.
- Improved and enabled filing referral for 2020, a feature for rewarding successful referrers with PayTM.
- Improved and enabled filing rewards for 2020, a feature to reward tax payers using the platform.
- Migrated filing rewards to Kubernetes to save cost and execution time improving overall experience.
- Worked on UI as well as backend for filing rewards for 2020 and enabled it afterwards to GA.



API Developer Intern

PredictivEye Inc.

Apr 2020 - Jul 2020 (4 months)

- Used JavaScript and AWS as backend and HTML and CSS as frontend to implement AI powered A/B testing chatbot. (Deployed to client)
- Used NodeJS and AWS as backend and ReactJS as frontend to implement a dashboard for A/B Testing which could be used by clients to start their own A/B test campaigns. (Deployed to PredictivEye)
- Used AWS and JavaScript to improve the FAQ chatbot adding Button support, Additional query support, and UI changes. (Deployed to client)



Videographer/ Editor and Sponsorship Team Member

Mailer Daemon

Feb 2017 - Jun 2020 (3 years 5 months)

- Shot and Edited videos related to College Issues and Other journalism things.
- Dug Deeper into Issues Related to College and Tried to Post the True Story based on them.



Software Development Engineering Intern

Clear

May 2019 - Aug 2019 (4 months)

- Used C# as backend and HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap as frontend to improve Rewards and Referral on ClearTax. (Deployed to cleartax.in)
- Used C# as backend to improve Form 16 parsing to an extent of 13% for salary breakup & up to 90% for big TANs. (Deployed to cleartax.in)
- Improved Validations for parsing, Improved ticket support, and did UI changes to more info page. (Deployed to cleartax.in)



🟂 Backend Intern

medicento

Mar 2019 - May 2019 (3 months)

- Implemented NodeJS & ReactJS.
- Researched on DB related challenges.

Summer Intern (Research Assistant)

HPC Lab, School of Energy Sciences and Engineering, IIT Kharagpur May 2018 - Jul 2018 (3 months)

- Used Numba to reduce the running time of a Python Script from 1.5 days to 36 minutes.
- Decluttered the Python script to perform faster.

Beta Tester

SHAREit Group

Dec 2017 - Mar 2018 (4 months)

- Tested new beta builds, reported and fixed minor bugs, and did promotions.
- Provided feedback for new builds.

Co-Leader, Creative Team (Trainee) And Blog Writer

Mayash

Dec 2016 - Dec 2017 (1 year 1 month)

• Developed creative ideas for marketing and content.

Co-Founder/Graphic/Android Developer

hubISM

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017 (9 months)

- Made the app out of scratch in a team, contributing mainly to frontend.
- Maintained the App for a small span of time.

R₩ Member

RobolSM - Robotics and Artificial Intelligence Club

Oct 2016 - Aug 2017 (11 months)

- Worked on Arduino Projects.
- Worked on Hardware Projects.
- Worked on Bluetooth Module.

✓ Intern

Futwork

May 2017 - Jun 2017 (2 months)

- Completed "Virtual Heroes Programme" at "Frapp".
- Invited 5 new members to the Frapp community.

Education



Indian Institute of Technology (Indian School of Mines), Dhanbad

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical Engineering Technologies/Technicians
Jul 2016 - Jun 2020

- Served as a Placement Team Member for Electrical Engineering Society.
- Served as the Student Co-ordinator for Electrical Engineering Society.

• Served as Co-ordinator and Organizer for Various Fests.

Bengali Senior Secondary School

Secondary and Senior Secondary, Science

Apr 2011 - Apr 2015

• Winner of Several School level Academic and Extra-Curricular Scholarships.

Licenses & Certifications

AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native on Coursera - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

AX3H54Y9GMHZ

- in JavaScript Skill Test LinkedIn
- in HTML Skill Test LinkedIn
- in AWS Skill Test LinkedIn
- HackerRank Problem Solving HackerRank 9CFC3B09852A

Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Java • Continuous Delivery • Competitive Programming • JavaScript • AWS CloudFormation • API Testing • Mockito • JUnit • Debugging

Honors & Awards

- Qualified for round 2 of "Google Code Jam 2018" Google
 Apr 2018
- Solved 3 problems in "Online Round ACM ICPC 2017-18" a competitive coding contest organised by "baylor.edu" on "CodeChef" (4 problems in practice round of the same) ACM and "baylor.edu"

 Nov 2017
- Secured 2591 rank out of 21038 teams in "CodeChef SnackDown 2017" CodeChef
 May 2017

- Won a silver medal each in Week of Code 38 and World CodeSprint 13, and a bronze medal each in 101 Hack 53, 101 Hack 55, and HourRank 29 organised by "HackerRank" HackerRank
- Placed 26th among 46 teams in "Hackfest'17" for making an android app called "hublSM" (source code in Github profile). Hackfest IIT ISM Dhanbad Jan 2017
- Competed in a team of three members in "Concetto 2k16" Secured 1st position in Round 1 and 4th position in the final Round 2 of "CodeVenture" Concetto IIT ISM Dhanbad Sep 2016
- Secured 2nd Rank among IIT (ISM) Students in "D'Code Monks v3 Div3" organised by "SIAM-IIT(ISM) Coding Cell" in association with "HackerRank" SIAM-IIT(ISM) Coding cell

 Dec 2016
- Appeared in "Regional Mathematics Olympiad" organised by "Homi Bhabha Centre For Science Education (HBCSE)" in 9th standard HBCSE

 Jan 2012
- Organised "CodeAThon" a coding event in "VIBHAV 2017" the official techfest of "Electrical Engineering Society, IIT (ISM) Dhanbad" - Vibhav IIT Dhanbad Dec 2017
- Organised "LaserTag" an informal event and Manthan formal events in "Srijan 2018" the official socio-cultural fest of "IIT (ISM) Dhanbad" Srijan IIT ISM Dhanbad

 Mar 2018
- Awarded several cash scholarships and certificates of merit for academic excellence, handwriting and general knowledge throughout the schooling period Bengali Senior Secondary School

 Jul 2015
- Participated in "50 hours of film making" organised by "Lights Camera ISM" and made a short film of 5 minutes posted on the official channel of "LCI" on "YouTube" Lights Camera ISM
 Oct 2016

Featured at The Scribbled Stories - TEDx IITDhanbad and The Scribbled Stories Oct 2017

Blog - https://thatfadedrainbow.wordpress.com/

Post - https://m.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=2108213002525804&id=1156243537722760&p=12

Competitive profiles - Codechef, HackerRank, and HackerEarth

HackerRank Highest Rating: 1996.62, Percentile: 96.06

HackerEarth Highest Rating: 1602, C++ Competitive Percentile: 96.38

CodeChef Highest Rating: 1849, 4 Stars

Total Problems Solved: 344

HackerRank: DarkCoderNavV
HackerEarth: navneetdas53
CodeChef: darkcodernavv

Qualified and successfully solved 1 question in 2nd round of "SCPC 2018" organised by "Samsung" - Samsung

Jun 2018

Secured Under 350 rank across world in March and August Challenge Div 2 organised by "CodeChef" - CodeChef

Aug 2018

Secured 74th rank across world in "Coder's Legacy 2017A" organised by "KGEC" in association with "CodeChef" - CodeChef

Apr 2018

Organised "Battledore" - an intra-college badminton championship in which around 150 students participated

Feb 2018

- Secured 17th rank across world in "HourStorm #2" organised by "HackerEarth"
 - HackerEarth

Aug 2018

Secured 47th rank across world in "HourStorm #1" organised by "HackerEarth" - HackerEarth

Jul 2018

Secured 154th rank across world in "ProCon 2018" organised by "IIIT Delhi" in association with "CodeChef" - CodeChef

Aug 2018

Open source percentile - HTML: 86.18, C++: 82.77, JS: 81.52, Java: 78.49 - HackerEarth

Aug 2018
Glthub - https://github.com/gitNavV

Secured 56th Rank across world in "September Easy 2018" organised by "HackerEarth" - HackerEarth
Sep 2018